经历令人难以承受的启示前阶段
After an overwhelming pre-revelation
我在各处找到了一切人和事
I found everything and everyone everywhere
我这么说不是为了炫耀 但有些人
I don't say this to brag but some
称我为世界上最棒的寻宝者
called me the best treasure hunter in the world
没什么可找的了
There was nothing left to find
大部分时间我都处于
For most of the time I was under
水下 数世纪以来一直在寻找宝藏
water searching for things for centuries
我独自工作 我开展研究且独自开始
I worked alone I conducted research and started alone
但这很适合我
But that suited me
但当阳光闪现时一切都变了
But everything changed when the solar flare struck
人们陷入黑暗与混乱之中
People were plunged into darkness and chaos
所有现代电子设备都停止运转
All modern electronics stopped working
大多数东西现在都毫无用处
Most things were now useless
人们曾相信政府会掌控局面
People believed the governments would take control of them
可笑的欲望
Foolish desires
战士们夺取了权力 掌控了当地社区
Warriors seized power and took over the local community
掌控了政府 并占领了欧洲大部分地区
Took over governments and occupied most of Europe
六年后 他们曾以为
Six years after they thought
一切都会好起来
Everything would turn out well
当然 我知道等待我的是什么
Of course I knew what awaited me
饥饿的城市变成了坟墓
Starving cities became cemeteries
金钱失去了任何价值
Money had no value
没有药品也没有燃料
There were no medicines or fuel
疾病肆虐
Diseases took hold
或许我准备得更充分
Maybe I was more prepared
我生来就是幸存者
I was born a survivor
而且我很快就做了
我一直想做的事
And very quickly I did what I always do
我寻找各种东西
I found various things
只是现在的世界已经变得非常危险
Only the world was now a much more dangerous place...
（伦敦 - 英国）
（London - England）
基金中的资金告急
Critical in the Fund of Funds
非常简单
Very easy
O .G. I. D.
A. D. A. G. I. O.
我抓到你了
I got you
好的
All right
看看警察是不是回来了
To see if the police are back
嘿 老伙计
Hey old man
你在这干什么
What are you doing here
等一下
Wait a minute
你们不是真警察
对吧
You're not real policemen are you
包里装的是什么
What's in the bag
我觉得是小提琴
或许是中提琴
I think it's a violin. Maybe a viola
说实话 我看不出区别
Honestly I don't see the difference
怎么了 你会演奏吗
给我
Why? Do you play? Give
it to me
不 你不会想要这个的
No you don't want this
但我可以把里面的东西给你
But I'll give you what's inside
我会把子弹塞满你的嘴
I'll fill your mouth with bullets
你们抓不住我们所有人
You can't catch all of us
不 没关系
No it's all right
只要抓你就行
Just you
还有你
And you
我会开枪打你
And I'll shoot you...
肯定还有你
And definitely you
伙计们 抓住他
Guys catch him
该死
Damn it
威力真小
Weak explosion
呃
Eh
有
Did
找到吗 找到了
you find it? Yes
就在你说的地方
Exactly where you said
我派了几个人去那
但他们都空手而归
I sent a few men there but they came back empty-handed
有些人甚至没回来
Some didn't even come back
斯特拉迪瓦里小提琴
Stradivarius
黄金时期 1690-1700 年
Golden period 1690-1700...
非常好
Perfect
奥古斯特国王有
另一个任务给你
King August has another task for you
他现在
算是国王了吗
Is he... a king now
算是王室成员
They're royal
他认为这是
最安全的回归方式
He thinks it's the safest way back...
他想见你
He wants to see you
我差点丧命
就为了找这把
小提琴 所以不了 谢谢
I almost died to find these violins so no thank you
因为它们的珍贵
所以不了 谢谢
because of their majesty so no thank you
我要去造我的船
I'm going to build my boat
他愿意给你报酬
He's willing to give you a reward
而且报酬很丰厚
A very good one
足够买你梦想中的船
Enough for the boat of your dreams
任务在哪
Where is this job
在英吉利海峡对岸
On the other side of the English Channel
和他谈好的条件
As you negotiated with him
想想吧 杰克
Just think Jake...
这可能是新的开始
This could be a new beginning
如果我想要新开始
不会拿生命去冒险
If I wanted a new beginning I wouldn't risk my life for it
不 我们会安全送你去那
No we'll get you there safely
那里除了疾病
埃德姆的战士和音乐什么都没有
There's nothing there but disease warriors Edm and music
谢谢 不过
见到你我很高兴
Thanks. But I'm glad I saw you
杰克
Jake!
你看起来气色不错
You look great
很适合穿这身礼服
That suit suits you
我拒绝
Refusal
他宁愿自己造船
He'd rather build his own boat
你信吗
Can you believe that
太可惜了
That's a tragedy
最好给杰克出个价
Better make Jake an offer
一个他
无法拒绝的出价
An offer he won't be able to refuse
哦 老朋友
Oh friend
好吧 你来了
Well you're here
是啊
Yes
怎么了 我的小伙子
What is it my boy
芒果特里 你最喜欢的
Mango Terry your favorite
是啊
Yes
好孩子
Good boy
喜欢吗
Do you like it
我的小伙子 喜欢吗
my boy? Yes
干得好
Good job
上好的油
Excellent oil
你在这干什么
What are you doing here
摩尔
Moor
国王派我来的
The king sent me
至于那个任务
告诉他我不想要
As for that job tell him I don't want it
你当面跟他说
Tell him that to his face
他在垃圾填埋场等你
He's waiting for you at the landfill
哎呀
Well!
能帮我下去吗
Can you help me get down
哎呀
Well!
杰克
Jake!
进来
Come in
坐下
Sit down
坐下 我们谈谈
Sit down let's talk
告诉我
Tell me...
你怎么样
How are you
我来这干嘛
What am I doing here
我雇了很多人
但看起来
I hired many people but it seems that...
你是唯一能找到
别人找不到的东西的人
...you're the only person who finds things others can't
这是某种特殊技能
还是个人魅力
Is it some special skill or charisma
说到个人魅力
Speaking of charisma...
这些布料
These fabrics
很不错
Are excellent
很神圣的材质
Something divine
这音乐
This music
能让高大的男人都落泪
Makes even big men cry
或许在尝试组建
交响乐团之前
Maybe before trying to form a symphony orchestra
你得先解决
食物和干净水的问题
you should start with food and clean water
你觉得我们
没在努力解决
Do you think we're not trying to solve the problem
食物问题吗 杰克
这家伙嘴里
塞满了牛排还说这话
of food Jake? The guy is talking with his mouth full of steak
我只吃鱼
I only eat fish
你觉得收拾
这烂摊子很容易吗
你觉得
Do you think cleaning up this mess is an easy task? Do you think
我们只要打个响指
就能点亮灯吗
it's like we can just snap our fingers and turn on the lights
所有该死的基础设施
都被毁了
All the damn infrastructure has been destroyed
我们每天都在拼命工作
努力从头建设一切
Every day we're drowning in work trying to build everything from scratch
还在和沃尔科夫将军这样的人战斗
他们试图阻止我们
and fighting people like General Volkov who are trying to stop us
好 行吧
Yes all right
那家伙就算被文化砸到脸
也认不出文化是什么
That guy wouldn't recognize culture even if it hit him in the face
他就是混乱的代理人
He's an agent of chaos
他就想看着世界燃烧
然后统治灰烬
He wants to watch the world burn and rule over the ashes
而你看法不同
And you see it differently...
愤世嫉俗罢了
Cynicism
相信我 我跟你说的是真的 杰克
Believe me when I tell you this Jake
这不是我想要的工作
This is not the job I wanted
闪光爆发时
我们失去了人性
When the flare hit we lost our humanity
你也亲眼看到了
人们在黑暗中做的事
You saw for yourself what people did in the dark
没人想到
世界会垮得这么快
No one expected the world to collapse so quickly
世界陷入了恐慌
The world panicked
有些人变成了野蛮人
Some became barbarians
看看你自己
Look at yourself
你建造的那些菲尔迪什塔楼
Those Fildish towers you're building...
是为了困住野蛮人
保证安全
...to keep the barbarians out to be safe
不是每个人都像你这么
有想法 杰克
Not everyone is as resourceful as you Jake
他们没有你的能力和勇气
在这个新世界生存下去
They don't have your skills and courage to survive in this new world
他们需要保护
They need protection
没有这些城墙
很多人早就死了
Without these walls many more would be dead
那城墙外的人呢
What about those outside the walls
那些躲藏起来的人呢
What about those who are hiding
你不管他们吗
Do you leave them
不 杰克
所有人都受欢迎
No Jake. Everyone is welcome
包括你
Even you
富恩特斯部长跟我说
他不想横渡英吉利海峡
Minister Fuentes told me he doesn't want to cross the English Channel
对 我不想
No I don't
我坚决反对
I'm firmly opposed
或许是因为你
还没看到更广阔的前景
Maybe because you haven't seen the bigger picture yet
我不想看更广阔的前景
I don't want to see the bigger picture
大局既丑陋又艰难
The big picture is ugly and hard
也不尽然
Not entirely
我们正竭尽全力
恢复世界的美好
We're doing our best to bring back the beauty of the world
你是自由的人 杰克
You're a free man Jake
不受约束
Unrestrained
不用向任何人负责
You don't answer to anyone
我只需要风
I just need wind
我只想驾着我的船
离开这烂摊子
I just want to take my boat and leave this mess behind
我和这些人
都想要属于自己的世界 杰克
These people and I want our own world Jake
这次你要找的
又是什么
What is it that you should be hunting this time
独一无二的东西
The one
《蒙娜丽莎》吗
The Mona Lisa
在这该死的美景之中
Among all this damn beauty
我不想扫你的兴
你很棒
I don't want to ruin your mood you're great
但巴黎是最早
被烧毁的城市之一
But Paris was one of the first cities to burn
当然
Of course
但有些事你可能不知道
But there's something you might not know
闪光爆发时
法国政府
把所有国宝
When the flare hit the French government moved all national treasures
转移到了一个秘密避难所
to a secret bunker
从艺术品
到总统的银质餐具
Everything from works of art to the president's silverware
我怎么才能
进去呢
And how am I supposed to get in there
坐皇家飞机
由皇家飞行员驾驶
With a royal plane and a royal pilot
那我能拿到船吗
还有所有
So will I get the boat? With all the
必需的补给和食物
necessary supplies and food
我还会给你一个头衔
Ill give you a title too
要是富恩特斯是
国防部长的话
Well if Fuentes is the Minister of Defense...
那你 国王
能给我什么呢
...then what can you King do for me
文化事务总监
Director General of Cultural Lullage
哦 老朋友
Oh friend
是啊
Yes
我不会错过太多的 老伙计
I won't miss much old man
我会在你明白之前
就回来的
I'll be back before you know it
你怎么样
How are you
嗯 我还好
Well I'm fine
你呢
And you;
我觉得这是个很糟糕的主意
I think this is a very bad idea
你总是有点冒险精神
You always take a bit of a risk
是啊 既然我总是这样
那为什么还要
去地球最糟糕的地方呢
Yes since I always do that why go to the worst part of the planet
我在小屋里
留了很多食物和水
I left a lot of food and water in the hut
你能保证
如果我没能
Will you promise that if I don't
回来 你会照顾它吗
come back you'll take care of it? I have no one to ask
我觉得索莫基
不会忽悠我
I don't think Somoki is messing with me
我不确定它是否信任你
I'm not sure if it trusts you
我会尽量活下去
I'll try not to die
在我回来之前
保重
Take care until I get back
一切都会好的
Everything will be fine
令人窒息 对吧
Breathtaking isn't it
是啊 这里真美
Yes it's very beautiful here
我们要往这个方向走吗
Are we going this way
对
Yes
这里安全吗
Is this safe
严格来说 不安全
到处都是弹孔
Technically no... it's full of bullet holes
这些吗
These
不 这些是上周的
No these are from last week
跟那帮孩子
有点小误会
A little misunderstanding with some kids
国王在等你
The king is waiting
别迟到
Don't be late
我们先不告诉你详情
We'll leave you in the dark for now
投放点在这
离这个村庄不远
The drop point is here not far from this village
根据我们的情报
这里全是游击队员
According to our information it's all partisans here
之后你得往北走
去圣凯克
Then you need to go north to Saint-Cake
那是个被占领的城市
所以你得悄悄行动
It's an occupied city so you have to move quietly
像耳语一样轻
Like a whisper
像该死的老鼠一样轻
Like a damn mouse
到了市中心
你就能找到
我们的联系人了
Once you reach the city center that's where you'll find our contact
市中心
City center
这可够远的
That's quite a lot
我怎么在地狱般的地方
找到他们
How do I find them in this hell
别担心
他们会找到你的
Don't worry. They'll find you
一切都非常
机密 不能外泄
Everything is extremely confidential in cups
只告诉
知情的人
Only for those who know
是 我得知道
Yes I need to know
我需要知道什么
我得知道
What do I need to know? I need to
怎么从那
逃出来
know how to get out of there
游击队员会联系我
只要我拿到东西
对吧
The partisans will contact me as soon as I pick it up right
你明白吗 我会给你送
逃生装备
三小时后送到
You understand? And I'll send you escape equipment three hours later
三小时
Three hours
保重
这飞机到处都是洞
Be well. - This plane is full of holes
我没注意到
I didn't notice that
我们晚上十点起飞
We take off at ten in the evening
我的人
My man
好
Ok
好了 一切准备就绪
开始行动
All right everything is ready let's start
安全带坏了
The seatbelts are broken
别啰嗦了 老伙计
Give it a rest old man
这廉价尼龙
要是我们坠机了
根本没用 对吧
This cheap nylon won't help you if we crash right
好了 开始吧
Well let's do this
好了吗
好了 我再算几笔
All right? - Yes I'll just do a few calculations
是啊 我不确定 这个指示器
能不能正常工作
Yes I'm not sure if this indicator works properly
先这么算吧
Let's just say it does
我原以为我们会待在路中间 所以 ...
I thought we'd stay in the middle of the road so ...
哦 还是用降落伞吧 不管怎样
Oh better use the parachute for better or worse
好
Ok
拉这个就能打开降落伞 对吧
I pull this to open the parachute right
等等 你不再演示一次吗
Wait. Aren't you going to do this again
不
No
该死的门外汉
Damn amateur
对 你得拉这条带子
Yes. You have to pull this strap
拉哪条
Which one to pull
我不知道 大概在撞到地面前吧
I don't know. Probably before hitting the ground
冷静点 吃点东西
Calm down. Eat something
我带你偏离航线 好吗
I'm taking you off the flight path ok
开始震动了
It's starting to shake
好 冷静点
Ok. Calm down
好
Yes
该死 抓紧了 老伙计
Shit! Hold on old man
他们看起来像沃尔科夫的人
They look like Volkov's men
欢迎来到法国 混蛋
Welcome to France asshole
好 我们这么办
All right let's do this the following way
我试着从这边飞出去
I'll try to fly out from this side
不过得提前跳一点
But we have to jump a bit earlier
明白了
Understood
准备跳 注意安全带
Get ready to jump watch the belt
降落伞打开后 马上拉
When the parachute opens pull immediately
明白了
Understood
我们一起降到 4000 英尺高度 然后你就得跳了
We'll go down to 4000 feet together then you'll have to jump
抓到了吗
抓到了
Did you catch it
Yes
我准备好了
I'm ready
别啰嗦
Give it a rest
我一打开就拉
As soon as I open it I'll pull
该死
Damn it
我就知道这是个坏主意
I knew this was a bad idea
什么
What
快点 老伙计 跳
Come on old man. Jump
该死
Damn it
这真是个坏主意
That was really a bad idea
不许动
Don't move
小心点
Be careful
看看他们
Let's take a look at them
抓住他们
Grab them
前进
Forward
小心 前进
Careful! Forward
再见 祝你好运 有人在等你
Goodbye and good luck. They're waiting for you...
圣凯克在这边西边
Saint-Cake is west of here
给我露出你的屁股 我让你看看我这张丑脸
Show me your ass! I'll show you my ugly face
下一个
Next
坐下 垃圾
Sit down trash
很难找到像样的对手
Hard to find a worthy opponent
这场博弈教会了我很多
This game has taught me a lot
但最重要的一课是 要尊重强大的对手
But the most important lesson is to respect a strong opponent
我在监狱里学会了下棋
I learned to play chess in prison
而监狱本身就像是角斗士的战场
And prison itself is a kind of gladiator arena
一个挑战接着一个挑战 永远在争夺权力
One challenge after another always fighting for power
一开始很可怕
At first it was terrifying
当我发现国际象棋 我找到了改变生活的东西
When I discovered chess I found something that changed my life
和比我强的人对弈 我也变得更强了
Playing against those better than me I also became better
直到我遇到了那个长官 我才进步了
It wasn't until I met the officer that I improved
我就是来求你这个
And that's exactly what I'm asking you for
全力以赴
Give it your all
你不会下棋 对吧
You don't know how to play do you
下一个
Next
沃尔科夫 一小时前我们的一门重炮击中了那架飞机
Volkov. One of our heavy guns hit the plane an hour ago
什么型号
What model
单引擎 可能是阿尔蒂诺夫 有降落伞的痕迹
Single engine. Probably an Altinov. Parachute traces...
好
Ok
给每个帮派 每个线人 每个士兵发消息
Send a message to every gang every informer every soldier
找到我们要找的人 赏一千发子弹
A thousand bullets for anyone who finds our guest
再准备好火车
And prepare the train
有多远
How far is it
80 公里 有人在圣凯克附近看到他了
80 kilometers. He was seen near Saint-Cake
忠诚市民的午餐发放将于下午 4 点开始
Distribution of lunch for loyal citizens will take place at 4pm
宵禁仍然有效
The curfew remains in effect
违反沃尔科夫将军的规定 将面临立即且严重的后果
Violation of General Volkov's rules will have immediate and serious consequences
宣讲结束 清理广场
The presentation is over. Clear the square
喂 你
Hey you
嘿 伙计们
Hey guys
把包放下
Leave the bag down
孩子们 我不想惹麻烦
Kids I don't want trouble
把包放下
Leave the bag down
你死定了
You're dead
你大概就是我的联系人吧
You're probably my contact
干得好 天才
Good job genius
杰克
Jake
对
Yes
这事儿我自己也能搞定
I could have organized this on my own
拜托
Please
你一直待在这儿 为什么不早点行动
You've been here the whole time why didn't you do something earlier
我只是想看看能不能把他们引出来
I just wanted to see if I could draw them out
我能照顾好自己
I can take care of myself
安德里亚 跟我来
Andrea Follow me
真恶心
That's disgusting
好了 既然我已经跟你碰头了 就快点
All right now that I've met you do it quickly
因为他们很快就会来找我们了
because they'll be looking for us soon
你为什么要割他们的喉咙
Why do you slit their throats
我父亲以前是屠夫
My father was a butcher
过来
Come
别站在那儿 别回头看
Don't stand there don't look back
看着地面
Look at the ground
难道
Could it be
是
It is
出血了
Bleeding
我们得做点什么
We need to do something
欢迎
Welcome
谢谢
Thanks
你想
Do you want
吃点什么吗 不了
something to eat? No
或许
Maybe something
喝点什么 不了 谢谢
to drink? No thank you
神父 恕我直言 我一进入交战区
Father with all due respect as soon as I entered the war zone
这辈子第一次从飞机上跳下来 差点被马车撞到
I jumped out of a plane for the first time in my life almost hit by a carriage
还遭到了士兵袭击 而她就只是看着
was attacked by soldiers and she just watched
所以我想直奔主题
So I want to get to the point
告诉我该去哪 我就去哪
Tell me where to go and I'll go
耐心是一种美德 我的孩子
Patience is a virtue my son
一件一件来
One thing at a time
多姆和露露找到了这张地图
Dom and Lulu found this map
他们却就这样在广场上被杀了
They were just killed in the square
是 当然
Yes of course
难道
Could it be
就这样了
That's all
灵魂区域
Soul area
什么
What
这就是个普通的花园
It's just a regular garden
这是什么
What is this
可能是密码
It might be a code
我去准备车
I'll prepare the car
我会照顾你
I'll take care of you
好
Ok
跟我来
Come with me
你喜欢吗
Do you like it
桌子
Table
是 是
Yes yes
在这一片丑陋之中 能看到一点美好真好
It's nice to see a bit of beauty in all this ugliness
你确实像奥古斯特说的那么厉害
You really are as good as August says
他怎么说
What does he say
他说你是最棒的
He says you're the best
我确实是
And I am
不 我不是奥古斯特的贵重资产之一
No I'm not one of August's valuable assets
奥古斯特的势力延伸到了这里
August's power reaches here
我在这没什么要恢复的
I have nothing to revive here
准备好了
Ready
好
Yes
Ok
对我来说 信任比权力更重要
Trust is more important to me than power
我不信任奥古斯特
I don't trust August
那你为什么在这
So why are you here
我也在想这个问题
I've been wondering that too
和所有人一样 奥古斯特有你想要的东西
Like everyone August has something you want
他的一个优势
One of his advantages
是
Yes
你呢
And you
我
I
我在这是为了确保能从 A 点到达 B 点
I'm here to make sure we get from point A to point B
真的
Really
该死
Damn it
我们走
Let's go
神父
Father
最先到达那里非常重要
It's very important to get there first
难道你不
Don't you
跟我们一起去吗 不了
want to come with us? No
每个人都有自己的赎罪之路
Everyone has their own path to redemption
我的任务是节省时间
My task is to save time
而你的任务是 相信自己的勇气
And yours is to believe in your courage
整座城市都被封锁了
The whole city is blocked
沃尔科夫在每条路上都部署了坦克
Volkov has placed a tank on every road
我们得穿过旧工厂 然后上东边的路
We need to go through the old factory and get on the eastern road
我喜欢这段 太喜欢了
I love this piece I love it
以上帝的名义 去吧
Go in the name of God
说真的 神父
Really father
所有人都到教堂来 出来
Everyone in the church come out
立刻举手出来
Come out immediately with your hands up
上帝知道可能是谁
God knows who it might be
马上出来
Come out now
不管你在哪
Wherever you are
好
Ok
谢谢
Thanks
我等不及想知道接下来会发生什么了
I can't wait to see what happens next
晚上好 先生们
Good evening gentlemen
为我们的健康干杯
To our health
我们知道你是谁
We know who you are
我们知道这里发生了什么
We know what's going on here
你不能再躲了 神父
You can't hide anymore priest
我没什么好躲的
I have nothing to hide
上帝看得见一切
God sees everything
其他人在哪
Where are the others
其他人呢
And the others
这里没有别人了
There's no one else here
只有我
Just me
那里找到的一切 都是上帝的杰作
Everything found there is the work of God
教堂现在关门了 但如果你想
The church is closed now but you can come in
忏悔你的罪过 可以进来
if you want to confess your sins
我是无神论者
I'm an atheist
当然
Of course
或许这样更好
Maybe it's better that way
因为宽恕罪过需要 意识到错误并有改正的意愿
Because forgiveness of sins requires awareness and the will to improve
而这些品质 你显然没有
Qualities you clearly don't have
因为你是黑暗的一部分 在这个苦难的世界里蔓延
Because you are part of the darkness that spreads in this afflicted world
而你 赢不了
And you... won't win
愿上帝原谅我 即将做的事
May God forgive me for what I'm about to do
不许动
Don't move
从车里出来
Get out of the car
我想引用一段启示录 第三章 第五十七节
I would like to quote this revelation Chapter three verse 57
你没必要这么做
You didn't have to do that
你没必要这么做 别催了 我不会喂他的
You didn't have to do that... Don't rush I won't feed him
该死 该死
Shit shit
该死的神父
Damn priest
说真的 该死的神父
Really damn priest
对了 你真不怎么样
By the way you're bad
带子
The strap
好 好
Yes yes
打开牢门
Open the cell
从这该死的门出去呼吸
Breathe through these damn doors
带我们离开这
Get us out of here
开火
Fire
稳住
Hold steady
跟紧他们
Follow them
走
Go
我们刚才是不是跳过马车了
Did we just jump over a carriage
我们就是跳过马车了
We just jumped over a carriage
头儿 检查通讯
Boss check the communications
不行
No
我们直着开
We're driving straight
这该死的是什么
What the hell is this
是防弹的
It's bulletproof
开火
Fire
向右转
Turn right
去哪
Where
进隧道
Go into the tunnel
快点
Faster
刹车
Brakes
这家伙有多少辆坦克
How many tanks does this guy have
杰克
Jake
该死
Shit
我们被包围了
We're surrounded
这下要乱了
This is going to be a mess
冷静 冷静 我不怕他们
Easy easy I'm not afraid of them
我更担心这个
This worries me more
左 左 左
Left left left
油箱 我知道
The tank I know
杰克 我知道
Jake I know
该死的奥古斯特
Damn August
那混蛋让我找 该死的《蒙娜丽莎》
That bastard told me to find the damn Mona Lisa
就因为他那破爱好
For all his damn greatness
还封了我个该死的部长头衔
And made me a damn minister
走 我们走
Come let's go
国王在我的射程里
The king is in my sights
我们的游击队员朋友有什么新消息
What's new from our partisan friends
杰克和达拉正前往斯武军事基地 执行任务
Jake and Dara are heading to the Swu military base on their mission
不幸的是
Unfortunately
萨姆森神父为我们的目标战斗时牺牲了
Father Samson died fighting for our cause
而且这是个重要的目标
And it's an important cause
愿他安息
May he rest in peace
你很棒
You're great
我有个问题要问你
I have a question for you
说吧
Go ahead
因为该死的 你们所有人都愿意去死
Because damn it all of you are willing to die
就只为了找到那张桌子吗
just to find that table
这和你有什么关系
What's it to you
你会得到
You'll get
钱 对吧 我不明白
money right I don't get it
这是件不错的艺术品 但所有
It's a nice work of art but all
这段经历都有点夸张了
this experience is a bit over the top
好吧
Well
有人喜欢桌子 有人喜欢航海
Some people like tables some like sailing
奥古斯特
August
萨姆森神父的事 我很抱歉
I'm very sorry about Father Samson
我认识萨姆森神父很久了
I've known Father Samson for a long time
在太阳闪光之前就认识了
Long before the solar flare
他为我们的目标做出了巨大牺牲
He made a great sacrifice for our cause
是 所以我才这么说
Yes that's exactly why I said it
为了一张桌子 这么多牺牲
So many sacrifices for a table
这不合理
That doesn't make sense
问题在于沃尔科夫
The problem is Volkov
他和蒙娜丽莎有什么关系
What does he have to do with the Mona Lisa
沃尔科夫也在找二号宝藏
Volkov is also looking for Treasure No. 2
如果他比我们先到那里
And if he gets there before us
里面所有东西都会是他的
Everything inside will be his
他们在那里留下的远不止普通艺术品
They left much more than just ordinary works of art there
食物 设备
Food equipment
武器
Weapons
所以
So
所以应该
So it should
让你从那里逃出来
get you out of there
什么
What
是 正是如此
Yes exactly
所以如果我们抓到他 你拿武器
So if we catch him you take the weapons
奥古斯特拿他的画 然后
August takes his paintings and
我拿我的船
I take my boat
正是
Exactly
嘿 杰克
Hey Jake
嘿
Hey
不管怎样
Well regardless
无论结果如何 我真的希望
of how it ends I really hope
你能找到你要找的东西
you find what you're looking for
我做了这艘小船
I made this little boat
谢谢
Thanks
真好
That's nice
我外婆教我折纸
My grandmother taught me to make origami
我们折了很多 然后让别人去发现它们
We made a lot of them and let others find them
我还知道怎么制作炸弹
I also know how to make a bomb
威力足够摧毁坦克的炸弹
A bomb powerful enough to destroy a tank
哇
Wow
嗯 这很好 但不幸的是 在如今的时代 （制作炸弹）更有用
Well that's nice but unfortunately in today's times it's more useful
是
Yes
好
Ok
我们走
Let's go
我们快到城市了 沃尔科夫
We're approaching the city Volkov
好的
All right
你抓到了什么人
Who did you catch
本来有更多人的 长官
There were more of them sir
但他们跑了 那个老头吗
But they got away - The old man
对 那个该死的神父
Yes that damn priest
但那里还有其他人
But there were others there too
多少人
How many
两个
Two
他们还有一辆大卡车
They also had a big truck
该死的会飞的卡车
Damn flying truck
你有坦克 还有 20 个人 （居然没抓住）
You had tanks... and 20 men
他们打了我们个措手不及 长官
They caught us off guard sir
他们突然冒出来的
They appeared out of nowhere
一个病男人和一个女孩
A sick man and a girl
在车里
In the car
他们往东边去了
They went east
还有什么
What else
我们抓到了那个神父
We caught the priest
长官 他对我们还有用
Sir he's still useful to us
你没必要杀我
You don't have to kill me
我不会杀你
I won't kill you
该死
Damn
不 不
No no
我已经告诉所有线人要留意
I have told all informants to be alert
我们很快就能找到他们
We will find them soon
我知道
I know
美国 法国
USA France
我们走吗
Shall we go
我们走
Let's go
国家宝藏就在这一带
The national treasure is around here
在其中一栋建筑里
In one of these buildings
该死
Damn
你感觉还好吗 不好
Are you feeling okay No
我状态不好
I'm not doing well
这就是灵魂区域
This is the soul area
我从这里进去
I'll go in from here
这该死的灵魂到底是什么
What the hell are these souls
闪光爆发前 这里
Before the flash here
关押着高度戒备监狱的囚犯
held prisoners from a maximum-security prison
他们是食人族 你明白吗
They are cannibals you know
这些人会吃掉他们杀死的所有东西
These people eat everything they kill
好吧 我们速进速出
All right we'll get in and out quickly
有人知道我们在这了
Someone knows we are here
对 我们走
Yes let's go
等一下
Wait a minute
该死 我们来晚了
Damn We're late
有人炸开了这扇门
Someone blew up this door
没有弹孔 没有损坏
No bullet holes no damage
看起来没人试图阻止这件事
It seems no one tried to stop this
他们可能把这里的所有东西都拿走了
They probably took everything from here
然后转移到了更安全的地方
and moved it to a safer place
你从哪拿到这张地图的 从巴黎
Where did you get this map From Paris
军事基地指挥官 斯特凡・马特奥将军那里
From the military base commander General Stefan Mateo
我们开始找吧
Let's start searching
这里有人遭到过袭击
Someone was attacked here
不 不是这样
No that's not the case
斯特凡・马特奥 他在这
Stefan Mateo He's here
斯特凡・马特奥 - 商务中心
Stefan Mateo - Business Center
撤离后 这里肯定有文件
After evacuation there must be files here
对
Yes
我们去找找
Let's find them
我找到这个了
I found this
这是法语的
This is in French
好 好 知道了
Okay okay got it
碰撞事故 破裂的水管
Collisions broken water pipe
未处理的两吨半卡车 食人族在聚集
Unattended two-and-a-half-ton truck Cannibals are gathering
背后起火
Fire on the back
需将所有珍贵物品转移至
Invitation to transfer all precious items to
坐标北纬 48°34'580557'3507
Coordinates North Latitude 48°34'580557'3507
南锡空军基地很合适
Nancy Air Base is very suitable
我不信
I don't believe it
什么 这很简单 我想
What It's very simple I think
绝对不能把这个留在这
We must not leave this here
让所有人都找到 这肯定是个陷阱
for everyone to find This must be a trap
难道 - 对
Could it be - Yes
他肯定加密了
He must have encrypted it
该死 现在怎么办
Damn what do we do now
走 我们得快点
Go we have to hurry
对 这是密码 把对应这个位置的字母给我
Yes this is the code Give me the letters corresponding to this position
地理纬度的米数
Meters from geographic latitude
好 我准备好了 48 34 58 05 57 35
Okay I'm ready 48 34 58 05 57 35
哇 太不可思议了
Wow That's incredible
不
No
该死 已经到了
Damn They're already here
走 我们走 得快点
Go let's go We have to hurry
给我一会儿时间
Give me a minute
我们得走了
We have to leave
西姆瑟霍夫
Simseerchov
西姆瑟霍夫堡垒 马济诺防线上第四大堡垒
Fort Simseerhov The fourth largest fort on the Maginot Line
肯定在这附近
It must be around here
就是这 西姆瑟霍夫 我们开始吧
This is it Simseerchov Let's start
杰克 杰克 我跟你说真的 我们必须这么做
Jake Jake I'm serious We have to do this
这里是马伦 1 号 马伦 2 号 能听到吗
This is Mullen 1 Mullen 2 Do you copy
这里是 2 号
This is 2
《蒙娜丽莎》的位置在西姆瑟霍夫堡垒
The Mona Lisa is located at Fort Simseerhov
重复 《蒙娜丽莎》的位置在西姆瑟霍夫堡垒
Repeat The Mona Lisa is located at Fort Simseerhov
收到 马伦 1 号 小队两小时后可抵达西姆瑟霍夫
Copy Mullen 1 The team can reach Simseerhov in two hours
重复 小队两小时后可抵达西姆瑟霍夫
Repeat The team can reach Simseerhov in two hours
收到 马伦 2 号 马伦 1 号 完毕
Copy Mullen 2 Mullen 1 Out
在这里
Over here
前进 前进
Forward forward
清理区域
Clear the area
我们走
Let's go
那辆会飞的卡车对我来说不算什么
That flying truck is nothing to me
听着 沃尔科夫
Listen Volkov
我们去南锡空军基地
Let's go to Nancy Air Base
或许不用去
Maybe we don't have to
我们去西姆瑟霍夫 在那我们会见到一位特别的女士
Let's go to Simseerhov We'll meet a special lady there
告诉火车司机让火车过桥
Tell the train driver to cross the bridge
桥被占了
The bridge is occupied
我想他是想要报酬 一千发子弹
I think he wants payment A thousand bullets
你觉得他值多少
How much do you think he's worth
三发
Three
我同意
I agree
西姆瑟霍夫堡垒
Fort Simseerhov
哇
Wow
我没看到任何键盘或生物扫描仪
I don't see any keyboards or biometric scanners
我看到那边和那边有摄像头
I see cameras over there and over there
这里有电
There's electricity here
过来
Come here
所有人都在这工作吗
Does everyone work here
是
Yes
不是吗
Don't they
这个能用
This works
这个也能用
This works too
通风系统
Ventilation system
靠太阳能板供电
Powered by solar panels
你找到什么了吗
Did you find anything
找到了 这声音来自通风过滤系统
Yes This sound comes from the ventilation filtration system
好 我们从这出去
Okay We'll get out from here
马伦 1 号
Mullen 1
沃尔科夫在向你靠近 距离 50 英里 重复 50 英里
Volkov is approaching you 50 miles away Repeat 50 miles
马伦 1 号 收到 他快到了
Mullen 1 Copy He's almost here
对 这些楼梯通向通风口
Yes these stairs lead to the ventilation
如果我穿过这根管道 再进入那条管道
If I go through this pipe and then enter that pipe
就能直接带我到宝库
It will take me directly to the treasure vault
好
Ok
如果通风机在运行 就把它关掉
If the ventilator is running turn it off
那如果没运行 我们该怎么办
What should we do if it's not running
总会有办法的
We will find a way
我们走
Let's go
还记得我们看到的那条维修通道吗
Do you remember the maintenance passage we saw
我猜它的电力是从这些太阳能板来的
I guess its power comes from these solar panels
我把它们全关掉
I will turn all of them off
好 开始吧
All right let's start
这样应该够了
This should be enough
这主意真差
This was a bad idea
该死 这里被淹了
Damn it this place is flooded
走 我们走 我就知道这主意不好
Come on let's go I knew this was a bad idea
文化部部长在我的辖区里
The Minister of Culture is in my jurisdiction
杰克
Jake
你还好吗 杰克
Are you all right Jake
你就是这样帮助这个世界的吗
Is this how you help the world
我本来想告诉你的 但奥古斯特不让
I wanted to tell you but August wouldn't let me
他做得对
He did the right thing
美国曾向日本投下两颗原子弹
The United States dropped two atomic bombs on Japan
“胖子” 和 “小男孩” 但其实还有第三颗
"Fat Man" and "Little Boy" but there was actually a third one
它被截留在了莫斯科
It was intercepted in Moscow
要是红军没有在马扎里受阻
If the Red Army hadn't been blocked in Marjaria
《蒙娜丽莎》
The Mona Lisa
这颗炸弹需要长时间才能引爆 所以他们装了火焰引爆器
This bomb needs a long time to detonate so they installed a flame detonator
没有内置引爆器 这颗炸弹就不会爆炸
Without the built-in detonator this bomb won't explode
所以奥古斯特要拿走炸弹 而你们所有人
So August is going to take the bomb and all of you
还不明白吗 奥古斯特不想用这颗炸弹
Don't you understand August doesn't want to use this bomb
他只是想让它远离沃尔科夫
He just wants to keep it away from Volkov
你就这么信他
Do you just trust him like that
我还有别的选择吗
Do I have another option
你本来有的 你不该把我卷进来
You had a choice You shouldn't have dragged me into this
他们总会找到他的
They would have found him anyway
你很清楚这一点 杰克
You know this well Jake
我对奥古斯特的信任 比对沃尔科夫多一点
I trust August a little more than Volkov
他们俩都是伪善的混蛋
They're both a bunch of hypocrites
我信任你 达拉
I trusted you Dara
对我来说 一切都结束了
For me everything is over
但如果我们能阻止沃尔科夫 也许别人还有机会
But if we can stop Volkov maybe others will still have a chance
要阻止他 得死多少人
How many people have to die to stop him
杰克 等等
Jake wait
留下来和我们一起战斗吧
Stay and fight with us
你难道不明白 像沃尔科夫这样的人 最后总能赢吗
Don't you understand that people like Volkov always win in the end
他们赢 而你们这些好人却不能 最后总能赢
They win but you good people can't They always win in the end
杰克
Jake
好
Ok
好 听着
All right listen
这条路通向加来
This road leads to Calais
奥古斯特的人在那里
August has his team there
他们在等着运走《蒙娜丽莎》
They are waiting to take the Mona Lisa away
你明白了吗
Do you understand
而且他把这事办得很好
And he handled this matter well
好 祝你好运
All right good luck
这不是你的战争 杰克
This isn't your war Jake
这不是你的战争
This isn't your war
被关押在这里的士兵
The soldier held here
很可笑 对吧
It's ridiculous isn't it
行动
Move out
各就各位
Take your positions
难道
Could it be
全体注意
Attention everyone
安全引爆器
Safety detonator
很可笑 对吧
It's ridiculous isn't it
我们像这世界的渣滓一样被关在牢笼里
We were locked in cages like the dregs of this world
再也见不到光明
Never to see the light again
但正是这光明将我们解放
But it was this very light that set us free
现在我们自由了 我们统治他们的世界
Now we are free and we rule their world
去加来
Let's go to Calais
之后再抓其他人
We'll catch the others later
行动
Move out
前进
Forward
达拉
Dara
哦 达拉
Oh Dara
达拉
Dara
我在这
I'm here
稳住
Stay calm
你说得对 这确实没意义
You were right this really makes no sense
你没必要回来的
You didn't have to come back
对不起 让你失望了
I'm sorry I disappointed you
对不起 我不该插手
I'm sorry I shouldn't have interfered
你从没牵扯过我
You never involved me
是我自己要离开的
I chose to leave on my own
但我们必须拿到那颗炸弹
But we have to get that bomb
怎么拿
How
你说过你能做一颗能炸毁马车的炸弹 对吧
You said you could make a bomb that destroys a carriage right
那火车呢
What about a train
杰克
Jake
火车正往城里开 要到目的地必须过桥
The train is heading for the city and it has to cross the bridge to reach the destination
我只需要拿到引爆器 不让火车停下
I just need to get the detonator and stop the train from halting
而你去炸桥
And you go blow up the bridge
难道
Could it be
达拉 你必须这么做
Dara you have to do this
但要做就得现在做
But if we're going to do it we have to do it now
好 准备好了吗
All right are you ready
准备好了 我们走
Ready let's go
你能走吗
Can you walk
能
Yes
达拉 快走 走
Dara hurry up let's go
好
All right
快点 快点
Hurry up hurry up
为什么这么晚 天这么黑
Why so late It's so dark
能见度也差 我必须晚点走
Visibility is also poor I have to leave late
等我们过桥开上直路 我来处理
When we cross the bridge and get on the straight road I'll take care of it
他不会喜欢的
He won't like this
我已经尽力了
I'm doing my best
蠢货
Idiot
我们机会不大
We have little chance
我知道 我们必须阻止他
I know. We have to prevent this.
对
Yes.
该死
Damn.
走
Go.
到十字路口右转
Turn right at the intersection.
好
Ok.
关灯
Turn off the lights.
好
Ok.
好吧
Well;
我担心能见度的问题
There is a concern about visibility.
我觉得没必要担心
I don't see any reason for concern.
但司机向我保证 他会尽全力
But the driver assured me that he is doing everything in his power.
是吗
Really;
我觉得他低估了自己
I think he underestimates himself.
我觉得你说得对
I think you're right.
我觉得他需要一点帮助 才能展现潜力
I think he needs a little help to show his potential.
就像你一样
Just like you.
将死
Checkmate.
再说一遍
Again.
我晚点走是因为 我们带着原子弹
I'm leaving late because we have an atomic bomb!
就这样吗
Is that all?
让我在桥上下车
Drop me off at the bridge.
去桥上
Go to the bridge.
那又怎样
So what?
有些人需要一点推动力
Some people need a little push.
也许你该去找他
Maybe you should go find him?
他在 而且他在等你
He's here! And he's waiting for you.
《蒙娜丽莎》对你来说可是块大肥肉
The Mona Lisa is a very big prize for you!
我不是来拿它的
I didn't come for her.
你是谁
Who are you?
杀手吗
A killer?
不是
No.
我只是个诱饵
I'm just bait.
胡子不错
Nice beard.
该死
Damn!
戏法不错
Nice trick.
杰克
Jake.
Jake!
杰克
怎么了
What happened?
你还好吗
Are you all right?
我没事
Yes, I feel fine.
你呢
And you?
我也没事
I'm fine too.
听到你没事我就放心了
I'm glad to hear that.
怎么了
What?
你看
Look.
杰克
Jake!
英国 萨里
Surrey - England
天啊 杰克
Oh my God, Jake.
你看起来就像刚和一群狼打过架
You look like you fought a pack of wolves.
差不多吧
Yes, something like that.
你那该死的《蒙娜丽莎》在峡谷底
Your damn Mona Lisa is at the bottom of the canyon.
我不知道现在是什么情况 但没有引爆器它就不会炸
I don't know what the situation is but it can't explode without this.
新的重大文化掠夺
a new major cultural plunder
或许不是
Or maybe not
我现在能休息了吗
Can I rest now
不 不 杰克
No, no, Jake
我无法想象会这么天真 认为没有其他沃尔科夫了
I can't imagine being so naive that there are no other Volkovs
不
No
不 我只希望 你不是他们中的一员
No. I just hope that you are not one of them
那么 是时候出发了 杰克
In that case, it's time to go, Jake
好好享受你的船吧
Enjoy your boat
我必须建立一个王国来统治
I have to build a kingdom to rule
广东绿皇香鸡   提供翻译《片名：余烬夺宝》